My friends and welcome to exercise number 89 in this exercise, we are going to implement that depth
first search algorithm in Najaf, so I will create a.
Graph containing four vertices diseases, zero one two and three zero connected to one zero, connected
to two one connected to two and two connected to three.
And we will start making the algorithm and executing the algorithm DFS in order to understand this and
Java.
So we are going to pass through all the elements and through all that know the vertices is in the graph.
But we are going also to start to specify to allow our algorithm to start from any position, not from
the default one, which is the numerical following.
The numerical order is zero.
So we are going to allow the DFS to start from like two, and we will see that the FC order algorithm
inside this algorithm in this inside this graph.
So let's start making and implementing the DFS in Java.
We start by creating a new Java class inside the resources folder.
I will create it as DFS graph.
So if you want to get all of the source codes, you can download them from the Resources folder in the
comments below and on our Udemy course.
So we start by creating an array of lengthiest called list specifying to think at least private link,
at least
link at list.
We can specify if there's an integer or we are not.
OK, so I will create it as informal program adjacent class of diaper right now.
Private Boolean
visit the array.
OK, so I will create an array of Boolean called visited and adjacent list.
OK.
This is very important.
Now let's initialize our our variables, our two lists.
These are that variables, the adjacent list and they're visited.
And remember when following the DFS, we are searching for the four.
We are visiting all the nodes.
All the vertices is.
We are not going to revisit them for that.
I have created a visited array to check if we have visited the vertices, so we are not going to add
to write it or add it to the adjacent list.
OK.
And the application in the next videos.
In the next couple of minutes, we are going to clarify everything.
So I will create a constructor graph and vertices this
weekend when we create a new and the first graph, the FSC graph object of this class in order to build
on.
And we need to specify here the vertices OK, equal here, creating, you know, list and visited equal
to a new Boolean.
And we start at index vertices four and five equal to zero by PI less than vertices is a plus plus.
We are going to add adjacent lists at the index ie equal to new link and this.
Look at this.
And here we go.
OK.
It's very simple.
We are going to create at everything a list, at every index adjacent list.
We are going to create a new index.
And for every vertex, we are going to get the adjacent list and to create it and apply at I vertex
and the application next.
In next couple of minutes, we are going to see how this and clarify this algorithm.
So let's create and method that add to add that had just so.
Edges here and edges here, let me go outside as well and the edges of voids and edges.
We took him to the perimeter and source and destination, and we specify adjacent layers and these are
sea see dot and the destination.
OK.
So.
At this finish, we are going to make this there is one problem here that interest me.
I have created the link at least here, but we didn't import anything in the Java framework.
But since we are creating this source code and I have a link at least five, so I have created an object
from this link at least.
So for that, please pay attention.
I have renamed this refractor link to listing and I need to import it again.
Import class here.
So here we are importing the linked list of Java.
Not that link at that we have created in the previous print because the add method we didn't create
it into.
I think at least a video.
OK, here I am, just making everything ever changes.
OK.
No, at this finish, we will continue.
So I will create now that DFS the algorithm.
Function, so I was pretty clear as I'll go.
I will create a method that it's done in time for it.
We start by creating pricing that never sticks.
We start by visited.
We start by birth and next tax equal to true, OK.
We put it as an remark at the vertex by true.
So it's very logical to do make and mark the vertex as true, because if I were told told you that,
hey, start from Vertex 10, so you will visit Vertex, then this line is telling us this and translating
it to doctor.
So system that out the brand end and the vertex, plus the space and I will create iterator iterator
of integer.
I will I.
Iterator adjacent list of at Fairfax, Vertex at the index vertex, so at least iterate.
We are iterating through this list.
So please, if you want to learn more about integrators and data or that Java framework, please go
to our course to complete Java Developer course on Udemy and you contact us.
We can send you that free component to Andrell free next.
If
we test, if we have, we didn't visit that code.
So if it is not at the visit, that if we are not, which is not contained in the visit that array,
then we called their method again the F s the F s method again, and we passed that Jason 30 metre as
the first.
So what we what we have done, we market have visited, the vertex has visited and we have added it
to the visit.
Now we present the vertex and iterate to recreate the iterator that we are going to search for, and
we looked through that Jason's list.
We start iterating through the all list.
We start by iterator and iterating to the next.
Moving the cursor to the next, next, next.
Every time, check if it is contained in the visitor.
Don't add that OK.
If it is not contained in visit that, so go and call the method again.
Otherwise, add it to the visit.
OK, so this is the algorithm.
Let's test it into the main class.
So public static void main with string args and we start by creating DFS graph and stance equal to the
new graph new.
The first graph and we passed the vertices.
Four.
OK, now let's make the connection.
Let's make the add.
Just so g that we have learned about the edges.
A previous video so that this finish, the source is zero and the destination is one g dot + add just
between zero and two.
+ +, +, + just between one and two, and at G dot edges between two and three.
OK, now system that out, that brand alarm following is there was the first traversal
or the or search.
OK.
G Dot we call DFS method and we start.
We specify here where what is the vertex that we are going to follow?
We are start from zero and let's run and see our program.
So run the FC program.
The first graph following as divert the depth for that depth first search.
OK.
Zero, one, two and three.